## Bio

Joe Letchford is a graphic designer from Richmond, Virginia. He specializes in graphic design, web design, art direction, visual identity systems, publications, and various print materials in the commercial and cultural sectors. Together with Josh Osborne, he runs the small enthusiastic non-geographic studio, Tiny Chime.

He believes strongly in experimentation and collaboration. His creative process involves looking beyond the specifications of each project to arrive at a meaningful solution through dialogue and close partnerships.

# Experience

Current / Washington, DC Design Army

Senior designer at Design Army focusing on branding, print design, and web design. Manage roughly eight to ten projects at one time with strict deadlines.

July 2015 → June 2017 / Minneapolis, MN MCAD DesignWorks

Graphic designer for the Minneapolis College of Art and Designs inhouse design team focusing on exhibition identity, branding, print, and publication design. Responsible for designing various advertisements for the college while also working with outside clients based in the Minneapolis and St. Paul area.

Feb. 2015 → May. 2015 / Richmond, VA RiggsWard

Previous freelance graphic designer at RiggsWard focused on print, branding, and web design. Responsible for multiple tasks such as internal identity redesign, front-end web redesign, and pre-production.

Dec. 2013 → Jan. 2015 / Richmond, VA Epiphany Studio

Previous graphic designer at Epiphany Studio.

May 2013  $\rightarrow$  Aug. 2013 / Washington DC Fathom Creative

Previous graphic design intern at Fathom Creative.

## Education

Minneapolis College of Art and Design Minneapolis, MN MFA in Visual Studies, 2017.

Virginia Commonwealth University Richmond, VA. BA in Anthropology, 2014.

### Proficiencies

Visual identity, typography, editorial design, ideation, print production, web design, html, css, functional prototyping, Sketch, Illustrator, InDesign, and Photoshop.

## References

Dylan Cole Studio Manager, MCAD DesignWorks dcole@mcad.edu 616.802.0614

Ryan Nelson
Senior Designer,
Walker Art Center
ryangerald.nelson@gmail.com
612.867.2276
makingknown.org
makingknown-flatfiles.tumblr.com

Josh Osborne Design Technologist, NPR josborne@npr.org 202.617.5228 josh.graphics